Emmanuel Agwu

Undergraduate Student

Personal Info

Address

Drumcairn Avenue Fettercairn, Tallaght Dublin 24 Ireland

Phone

0899425306

E-mail

mimiagwu@hotmail.com

Date of birth

1998-03-17

GitHub

https://github.com/EmmanuelAgwu

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuelagwu-7aa449117/

Skills

Java

C++

Play Framework

Python

SQL

HTML

JavaScript

CSS

Twitter Bootstrap

Database Management

R (programming language)

Customer Communication

Team Work

Summary

As an experienced Data Analyst, Sales Associate and Programmer my abilities could help your company achieve its goals. My excellent communication skills can help deal with any consumers problems that may arise. From my experience in work, understanding consumers and been able to efficiently communicate and help them will prove invaluable to your company. I am very outgoing, reliable, enthusiastic, and a friendly individual who has an experience supervising teams, gathering information and great interpersonal leadership. As an undergraduate student in Computer Science I know that have I have the necessary skills and experience to adapt in any situation.

Skills & Qualities

- Able to communicate effectively at all levels within an organisation.
- Creating test programs according to specification
- Providing Support in the event of software failure
- Suggesting improvement to usage of application and their design
- Excellent time management skills.
- · Great Teamwork skills.
- Self-motivated, Honest and Reliable candidate.
- · Very Committed to task given.

Project

For our Second-year project we had to design a virtual library system using Java HTML, CSS, SQL and Play-frame Work which follows the CRUD format which are the four basic functions of persistent storage. This system is meant to simulate that of the real-world library. Our system consists two Profile an Administrator profile and a User profile. The virtual library system consists of the following features, a point system to allow the User to loan a limited number of products (attached software), an extend feature to extend the User loan and a return system to refund the User points and an Add Update and Delete functionality.

When Signed in as A user you will have the option to:

- Borrow a Product
- Return a Product
- Extend a Products
- Download additional Software (PDF)

When Signed in as an administrator you will have the same option as the user but with extended features such as:

- Manage Information stored in the database
- Access pages that are restricted to guest and Users of the Library-System.
 These pages will include products and user's database
- Able to add, update and delete the products from the database and edit/delete users within the library-system

Education

Present

2017-05

2015-05

2017-09 - Institute of Technology Tallaght

Bachelor of Science in Computing.

Award Classification: Pass with Merit - Grade 2

2016-09 - Institute of Technology Tallaght

Higher Certificate in Science in Information Technology.

Award Classification: Pass with Merit - Grade 2

2012-09 - Mount Seskin Community College

Leaving Certificate Vocational Programme

- Achieved Perfect Attendance in Year 2015-2016
- Awarded A.C.E certificate upon Completing A.C.E Program.
- Award G.A.A silver medal 2012.

| Interpersonal |
|------------------------|
| Software |
| Windows |
| Teradata SQL Assistant |
| IBM SPSS Modeler |
| SQL Developer |
| R Studio |
| Ubuntu |
| Microsoft Word |
| Microsoft Excel |
| Microsoft Point |
| |
| Languages |
| English |
| German |
| laiba |

lgbo

Experience

2018-02 -05-2018-08-30

Eir MIS Data Analyst

1, Heuston South Quarter, St Johns Road, Dublin 8

- Designed and contributed to various automated programs and predictive data learning models using languages such Python 3, C#, C++, Java, IBM SPSS MODELER, ARC GIS, Teradata SQL
- Maintained automated reporting solutions with Python 3.
- Developed SQL Queries according to requirements specification
- Worked in an Agile based Development when designing and reporting SQL and Python scripts
- Maintained accurate documentation to all reports related to the Analytics Centre of Excellence team
- Displayed excellent technical skills and productivity while producing reports for customers within the Analytics Centre of Excellence.
- Efficiently demonstrate technical project and team management skills to meet companywide reporting requirements
- Analysed key business reports and recommended solutions.

2015-03-09 2015-03-22

Sales Associate

Super Value Fortunestown Shopping Centre, Maplewood Rd, Springfield, Dublin 24

- Responsible for ensuring that customer enquiries are resolved at first point of contact,
- Clean and supply designated facility areas (dusting, sweeping, vacuuming, mopping,
- cleaning ceiling vents, restroom cleaning etc).
- Perform and document routine inspection and maintenance activities.
- Carry out heavy cleansing tasks.
- Notify management of occurring deficiencies or needs for repairs.
- Adjusted and minor repairs.
- Stocked and maintain supply rooms.
- Cooperate with the rest of the staff.
- Followed all health and safety regulations.

Interests and Hobbies

During my free time I enjoy drawing and making up new concept art for future game projects. I also like to mess around with photo manipulation and 3D software's such as Adobe Photoshop, Premier pro, Gimp,3D coat and Zbrush personally I find it one of the best ways to relax.

I Also like keeping up with the latest technology. These types of technology include mobile phones, Virtual Reality, video games techs and computer languages hobbies It's because of video games I initially got into concept Art and coding which I enjoy so much. I also like to keep active by playing basketball, jogging or cycling and whenever I get the chance.

References

References are available on request